thebetterindia.com 2019-09-21

# Privacy Policy - The Better India

TheBetterIndia.com is a website owned and operated by Vikara Services Private Limited which is a content production company. Vikara Services Private Limited (known as ‘The Company’) publishes content in the form of text-based articles, videos, images and audio files.

This Privacy Policy covers The Company’s treatment of personal information that it gathers when you are on its website and when you use its services. This policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that The Company does not own or control, or to individuals that The Company does not employ or manage.

 **Information Collected by The Company**  
We only collect personal information that is relevant to the purpose of our services. This information allows us to provide you with a customized and efficient experience. We collect the following types of information from our users:

 **Information You Provide to Us:**  
We receive and store any information you enter on our website or provide to us in any other way. You can choose not to provide us with certain information.  
We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. The Company and its authorized agents automatically receive and record certain “traffic data” on their server logs from your browser including your IP address, Google Analytics & other analytics’ cookie information, and the page you requested.  
The Company may collect and, on any page, display the total counts that page has been viewed.

 **E-mail Communications**  
The Company is very concerned about your privacy and it will never provide your email address to a third party without your explicit permission, as detailed in the “Sharing Your Information” section below. The Company may send out e-mails with selected content. If you do not want to receive e-mails from us, please click on the ‘Unsubscribe’ link that is present in every e-mail.

 **Cookies**  
Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and tell us how and when pages in our website are visited and by how many people. The Company’s cookies do not collect personal information, and we do not combine information collected through cookies with other personal information to tell us who you are or what your e-mail address is.

 **Sharing Your Information**  
Because The Company enables people to discover and share content with one another, information about the people who use The Company is an integral part of The Company’s experience. Rest assured that we neither rent nor sell your personal information to anyone and that we will share your personal information only as described below:

The Company Personnel: The Company personnel and authorized consultants and/or contractors may have access to user information if necessary in the normal course of The Company’s business.

Business Transfers: In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Moreover, if The Company, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred. The conditions of this Privacy Policy will be binding and applicable on all entities who may acquire your personal information as part of the transferred assets.

Protection of The Company and Others: We may release personal information when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to comply with a law; to enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other policies; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of The Company, our employees, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

Syndication: The Company allows for the RSS syndication of all of its public content within the The Company website.

With Your Consent: Except as noted above, we will contact you when your personal information is shared with third parties or used for a purpose incompatible with the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected, and you will be able to opt out to prevent the sharing of this information.

 **Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
The Company may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time, at its sole discretion. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make changes to the Privacy Policy, we will notify you by posting an announcement on the The Company website so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances if any, it is disclosed.

 **Conditions of Use**  
If you decide to visit The Company-owned websites, your visit and any possible dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use, including limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes, and application of Indian law.

 **Effective Date of this Privacy Policy**  
This Privacy Policy is effective as of February 2015.
